

COMPUTER SCIENCE PHD STUDENT · RUTGERS, NEW BRUNSWICK

A2, Seethalakshmi Flats, No 32, Patel Street, Nehru Nagar, Chromepet, Tamil Nadu - 600044.

□ (+91) 9677059650 | ■ krishnan.gosakan@rutgers.edu | 🏕 krishnangosakan.github.io/KrishnanGosakan | 🖸 KrishnanGosakan

Summary

A software engineer and researcher with 6 years of coding experience. My area of interest is in computer systems, ranging from compilers to system security. I am specializing on operating systems and computer architecture for my PhD research, with concentration in memory subsystem. I am switching to academia, after 6 years of professional experience, to pursue my doctorate in computer science. I am a logical thinker and analytical in nature. I learn things quickly. I am looking forward for a research career, where I wish to improve user applications and operating systems for next generation computer architecture.

Education

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

New Brunswick, New Jersey

Aug. 2022 - Present

DOCTORATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- · Advisor: Prof. Sudarsun Kannan
- · Working on a multi institute collaborative project on improving virtual memory for next-generation processors
- My contribution deals with improving TLB efficiency by reducing it's miss rate
- Implemented the idea in gem5 architectural simulator
- Evaluating the design against workloads like graph500, XSBench, BTree

Sri Sivasubramaniya Nadar College of Engineering

Kalavakkam, Tamil Nadu

Aug. 2012 - July. 2016

B.Tech in Information Technology

- Placed in First class with a CGPA of 7.153
- · Final year project:Inter-video comparison for redundancy identification using python and mongodb database
- Project Advisor: Prof. E.M. Malathy
- Implemented a File Management System using Front-end as java and Backend as oracle database as a mini academic project
- Created a Banking Account Creation and Management software using Java as front-end and MySQL as back-end
- First prize in programming contest in SSN EEE symposium

Smt Ramkuwar Devi Fomra Vivekananda Vidyalaya

Chromepet, Tamil Nadu

July. 2012

HIGHER SECONDARY, 12TH

- Board: Tamil Nadu State Board
- Subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology
- Scored 1121 marks out of 1200 with an Engineering cut-off of 196.50

Smt Ramkuwar Devi Fomra Vivekananda Vidyalaya

Chromepet, Tamil Nadu

SECONDARY SCHOOL, 10TH

- Board: Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE)
- Subjects: Mathematics, Science, Social
- Scored CGPA of 9.6 out of 10
- Participated in various science quizzes
- Extracurricular Activities: Chess, Yoga

May. 2010

Work Experience ___

Zoho Corporation Chengalpattu, Tamil Nadu

MEMBER TECHNICAL STAFF

Feb. 2017 - July. 2022

- Worked as a C++ developer for Zoho Assist native Windows application and installer
- · Responsible for design, implementation, testing and customer support for Zoho Assist service and deployment components
- Module owner of Windows Deployment for Zoho Assist Unattended Installer
- Have experience in Microsoft GPO and Intune deployment technologies
- Worked on building an MSI based installer for Zoho Assist Unattended Support
- Developed a C# application for bulk deployment of Zoho Assist Unattended support InstallShield-based installer in domain or workgroup based windows network.
- Designed and developed a load testing framework for Zoho Assist
- Designed and developed version update system with failure detection using MD5 hash for Zoho Assist
- Reported SQL injection and XSS bugs in multiple Zoho products
- · Reported privilege escalation and injection based security issues in Zoho Assist as a part of HackFox internal security hackathon

August 22, 2022 Krishnan Gosakan · Résumé 1

Cognizant Siruseri, Tamil Nadu

PROGRAMMER ANALYST TRAINEE

Aug. 2016 - Jan. 2017

- Trained on Mainframe Technology and Cobol programming language
 Worked on IBM Z mainframe systems
 Awarded as the Best Student of the Batch